Hello everyone, I'm Sherry from Marvelous Designer.
Tonight, I'm going to show you how to make a suit out of Marvelous Designer.
Good evening, everyone.
Let's get started.
First of all, I'd like to tell you that today's live stream may be a bit long.
Thank you for coming so early.
The content of today's live stream, according to the order, is to talk about shirts and socks first.
Then it's pants.
Then it's a suit jacket and some special crafts in the suit.
There will be a live broadcast tonight.
You can see in the lower left corner that I have written that there will be a live broadcast.
We will have a live broadcast every time we live.
Then we can start to prepare.
You can prepare some melons and snacks first.
Then, if you have any questions during the live broadcast, you can ask them at any time.
OK.
I will reply to the chats in real time.
So if you have any questions, just ask them directly in the chats.
First of all, before we start making the suit, we need to introduce a virtual model.
You can introduce your own virtual model.
Or like this.
You can introduce a virtual model from the software folder.
Here, in order to make it easier, I didn't change the text.
I see the black and white surface.
Then in the upper left corner, our library window here.
In Marvelous Designer 11, you can switch to Modular Configurator here.
Its Chinese is called the modular controller.
In the modular controller, you can do it.
Put different parts on the suit together.
For example, you can match different sizes, or sleeves, or necklaces.
Today, it is expected to be about 10.5.
In the upper right corner, it is like this.
If you are a Marvelous Designer 10, or a previous version of the user.
Because Marvelous Designer 11 has made major changes to the interface.
So if you are in the old version.
If you want to use the function of Modular Configurator.
The function of the modular controller.
You have to go to the upper right corner of your screen to find it.
In the upper right corner, you can switch to this mode.
Then we come to the Modular Configurator.
Double-click this folder.
We can see the corresponding icon here.
After double-clicking this icon.
Various pairs will pop up at the bottom.
This is the module library.
One of them is a module.
Here, you can enter different necklaces according to the need.
Or the size and the sleeves.
There are many types.
There are short-sleeved T-shirts, long-sleeved T-shirts.
There are also some suit jackets.
For women, there will be some.
It's almost like a coat.
Oh, right.
Then when you open this Modular Configurator.
We can double-click to load different accessories.
There are two types of sleeves here.
You can check its shape according to the need.
See which one you want.
This is a split sleeve.
It's a two-piece sleeve.
You can see that it's open in the middle.
Generally speaking, we have this different sleeve structure for shirts and suits.
One is a two-piece sleeve.
It's to make the curve here closer to the arm.
The other one is a one-piece sleeve.
This is the sleeve we use more often.
Here, I choose to use this one-piece sleeve.
Then you can put other parts in according to your needs.
These are some of our existing accessories.
Then we freeze these panels.
Then change the position of the virtual model.
When the panel is frozen.
These changes will not affect the frozen panels.
But you have to pay attention to the frozen panels.
They are still in conflict.
So if you have other panels.
Then you'd better freeze them all together.
Okay, then we'll freeze it again.
In this case, the clothes and the model's posture will match.
Okay.
After that, we can see that.
The module is relatively old.
We created the system.
So it has some panels.
It may not be symmetrical.
In this case, we can delete the sleeves on one side.
Then select the other side.
Press Ctrl D to create a symmetrical panel.
Then put it aside.
Okay, after that.
We can see here.
Because of our front here.
We also used different structures.
So there is a problem.
It can't be symmetrical on the left and right.
Then we can cut off the panels.
Then see if they can be set to symmetrical panels.
Or we can keep this panel.
Then select the front here.
Press Ctrl D.
Create it into a symmetrical panel.
In fact, everyone should know.
The main purpose of creating symmetrical panels.
It's just for convenience.
Wait a minute.
After we modify one panel.
The other side will be modified.
The other side will be modified in conjunction.
Then the seam line here.
We can see it.
There may be some small problems.
It is not symmetrical on the left and right.
Then we are here.
Just manually sew it together.
That's it.
Good evening, everyone.
After that.
We can cut off the panels here.
If you find that.
In the process of your use.
Although this panel is symmetrical on the left and right.
But if its seam line is not symmetrical.
We can cut it in half.
Then press Ctrl D.
Create a symmetrical panel.
It will be symmetrical on the left and right.
Good evening, everyone.
If you have any questions.
You can say it in the chat.
I see it will come back.
Then we sew the seam line.
So if you are for your own model.
To wear this shirt.
In fact, we have a lot of files.
You can find it in the model drawing library.
Here.
Because our door is folded.
So the seam line type is changed to turn.
Then look for it again.
Do you forget to sew the panel?
Then create the seam line between them.
Okay.
Then here.
You can see that there is no break in the middle.
So we have to switch to the free sewing tool.
To sew.
Because the line sewing.
It needs to identify a whole piece of sewing line.
Okay.
After we have created the seam line.
Press the control button to start the simulation.
Everyone usually in the process of creating clothes.
You also remember.
After you have created the seam line.
After the simulation.
You'd better change the perspective.
See if there is a missing seam line.
If there is.
Just sew them together.
Then here.
We will delete the excess points.
Combine the back and center here.
Lolita.
Look at the previous.
Okay.
Then we have to change the position.
The position of the back and center.
We will set it in the way that is not the opposite.
Just like this.
Okay.
The main thing in Lolita's clothes.
Is the design.
Not your own operation.
Uh.
Pants.
Like this.
Is.
Its version.
Not very difficult.
Okay.
Next we change the posture.
Change a move.
A little exaggerated posture.
In the process of everyone's usual production.
It is best to change these postures more.
For example.
Your arm.
Is more open.
It is more t post.
Because this is the right posture.
This is the right posture.
Because this is the posture.
Because this way we can easily check if your outfit is integrated or if it needs to be modified.
Yes, if the left and right sides of your board are combined, the left and right sides of this board are still symmetrical.
If you want to change your pose, you can watch the tutorial video about the virtual model.
If your outfit is hard, try to make it blue.
Don't make your outfit too tight, unless you are wearing a tight dress, like a swimsuit or a bunny dress.
If your outfit is too tight,
try to make it a little darker.
If your outfit is too red, it's okay.
Now that we are done with the shirt,
we are going to make the shirt more harmonious.
You can change the shirt according to your needs.
I am changing it because I think it looks too much like an anti-vibration sleeve.
You may not be used to this in your daily life.
However, you can use this habit in the future.
In this case, you should not look at the shirts.
The shirt and the uniform's sleeves are independant.
Sometimes they work with each other,
so you cannot adjust the pattern.
This is why I change the shirt all the time.
If you don't know what is reverse activation, you can watch the previous video, this is the most basic knowledge.
After the reverse activation of the plate, this plate will no longer participate in the simulation.
If you reverse activate with the ferrous wire, then the ferrous wire between the plates will not work together, which means that the plate will no longer exist.
It no longer participates in any form of simulation, there is no collision.
After the reverse activation of these two plates, let's take a look at the ferrous wire.
Now, without the effect of the ferrous wire, we can see that the ferrous cage is significantly larger.
So let's move the point of the ferrous cage inside to reduce the fabric under it.
Can you understand?
After we reduce this piece of fabric, press the control key to simulate.
You will see that there is a lot of fish under the fish.
From the previous fish, there are a lot of fish.
Now there are fewer fish.
Next, let's see if there is a lot of fish under the fish.
If you want to make a shirt that is close to the body,
first of all, the effect of this screen is the transparent picture.
After opening the transparent picture, you will see that it has a lot of parts that are out of the picture.
When we change clothes, we change it little by little.
If there are too many parts, you can move the points inside.
Then if you pack too tightly,
for example, the waist is too tight here,
you can move the two points separately to the outside of the board to modify it.
After we determine the shape of the furrow,
we will activate the sleeve board to simulate it together.
Or here, let's take a look at it.
The bottom of the page is relatively empty.
Then we can raise the two points of the bottom of the page a little bit.
Just to make it tighter.
What about the sleeves here?
The tighter the sleeve board, the more likely it is to have wrinkles.
Understand?
But you can't be too tight.
Look at my picture.
Did I just change the bottom of the page to the top?
Now, first of all, I only changed the sleeve board.
Are the sleeves and the sleeve board sewn together?
But I didn't change the sleeves.
This will cause the length of the sleeve board to be longer than the sleeve board.
So it will have wrinkles.
So it will produce such a strange wrinkle and pull feeling on the picture.
First of all, we use an edge sewing machine to check the length between the sewing lines.
You will see that it is red.
Why?
That is, it reminds you that these two sections are too different.
Then we will make the sleeve here a little shorter.
OK, after you make it a little shorter, you will see that it is more adherent.
But at this time,
we see that the sleeve will have some oblique shape.
This is the result of the fold, isn't it?
Then when we open the transparency chart with Alt 4,
you will see that the sleeve is pulled out.
That is to say, it is not a very natural, very loose,
a more harmonious dress.
It's a little tight.
So here at the bottom of our page,
you just pull it down a little bit,
give it more material,
so that it doesn't wear so tight.
Then we press the control button to start the simulation,
and try it.
When we usually change shirts,
you can be patient,
and then look for where there is more,
where there is less,
and then move it.
Don't move a whole thread,
and don't adjust it as a whole.
It's best to be precise,
where there is less,
we will add a little more,
where there is more,
we will reduce a little more.
Yes, all of our live broadcasts,
there will be replays.
But if you come to watch the live broadcast,
you can communicate with me.
If you don't know which step you are on,
you can ask me.
For example, if I don't explain this part to you,
you may not understand what I'm doing, right?
For example, like me now,
let's go back to the simulation just now,
and take a look.
Okay, first of all,
let's look at its connection,
which is the connection between the sleeves
and the shoulders.
Are there any protruding places here?
Well,
for auto fitting,
it can't be attached directly.
Auto fitting can only be adjusted automatically,
but there are a lot of details
that you still have to adjust manually.
Okay,
then we are here,
we can see that there is a protruding place here,
right?
Can everyone know
what caused this protruding place?
Or where are we going to change now?
Let's take a look.
Let's see if there are any children who can answer.
I don't think everyone knows.
In fact, it has a little bit of a relationship with the vermilion line,
but it's not a big deal.
Look,
did I squeeze out a corner here?
Yes,
is it a fish?
I saw that some children answered correctly.
The sleeve is too high.
What is the sleeve?
Just to give some children who don't understand,
the sleeve is this point
to the vertical line
connected between these two points,
just this height.
If it is too high,
you see,
if we cut it off,
there was a child before,
he was right.
If you see where there is one more,
you just draw a line here,
and then you follow this line
to remove the excess part.
In fact,
it can help you to adjust the board a lot of times.
Okay,
then we pull the sleeve down a little bit,
and then press the control panel to model.
You see,
it's very smooth now.
So when we change it,
we must have some planned reference,
or you can draw,
just like I said before,
you can draw some lines on the board
to find where there are more,
and then remove the excess part.
That's it.
Well, this is our shirt part.
Okay,
there is a point to tell you about the shirt here.
That is,
if you usually go to create this shirt yourself,
you must not understand what this piece is.
Let me explain to you first.
This piece is called the sleeve.
It is an opening.
Then I will delete all the sewing lines here first,
and then I will tell you how to sew this part of the sleeve.
Okay,
I will tell you how to sew this part of the sleeve
when I make this suit later.
Take your time.
Okay,
here,
we first use the free sewing tool
to sew the sleeve and the clothes together,
because the sleeve is a single small piece.
Then we can delete the excess internal line first.
It doesn't matter.
Okay,
then the next one is our skirt.
This is the pleats.
That is,
there are some of these things called pleats in the sleeve.
You may have used our software before,
and you may know that
this pleat looks more straight here,
because it is sewn up.
And then there are some fish on the top here,
which can make your arm loose.
Okay,
since the pleats,
the left and right sides of the pleats need to be sewn up,
so we first use the sewing tool to sew up the left and right sides of the pleats.
Here,
you see,
you can't use the sewing machine,
because it is not broken,
so we need to use the free sewing tool
to sew up the left and right sides.
Then remember to change the type of sewing line to TURN.
If you don't understand why this type of sewing line is TURN,
you can take a look at our previous tutorial videos
about pockets.
I won't go into detail here.
Okay,
let's start sewing the pleats.
This is the pleat.
Sew it up.
Use the free sewing tool first,
click here,
then move it over.
Then press the SHIFT key.
You see,
we have already sewn up the pleats,
right?
We started sewing from the pleats here.
Then you go to find the starting point of the next point corresponding to this point.
You see,
this pleat is sewn to this side,
right?
So this point starts from this point, right?
So when we use the free sewing tool,
remember to press the SHIFT key,
and then start sewing from this point to the side.
Okay,
now we start sewing to this point.
This pleat is sewn to the left and right sides, right?
So this point is actually this point, right?
Okay,
now that it is sewn to the left and right sides,
we don't care about it.
We just continue to sew from this point to the back.
We need to skip the fold.
Okay,
now if we sew to this point,
if you don't sew to this point,
but to this point,
then we skip to this point,
where the pleats are sewn to each other.
Do you understand?
At this point,
you may ask,
can I choose this point or this point?
Actually,
you can choose both.
But why do I sew to this point?
It is because there is a base in our software,
a basic knowledge.
That is to say,
it is better not to cross-layer sewing.
What does cross-layer sewing mean?
That is to say,
it is better not to hold a piece of fabric in the middle
to sew this layer outside.
Do you understand?
It doesn't matter if you don't understand.
You can watch the previous video.
It is because there is more content today,
I can't give you a very, very detailed basic knowledge
that I can't give you.
If you don't understand,
you can watch the last video to make shoes.
Finally,
let go of the Shift key,
and you can sew it all here.
Then this section,
press the Shift key,
because there may be some in the middle,
like this hollow point,
which means that the inner line is not connected.
Then we just press the Shift key,
and we can choose one section at a time.
Then sew the middle.
It is not possible to cross-layer sewing.
In simple terms,
you can't sew the first layer and the third layer together.
That is to say,
you can't sew the first layer
and the third layer together.
Because they still have the second layer in the middle.
If you want to sew,
you should sew the first layer and the second layer,
and then sew the second layer and the third layer,
instead of crossing the second layer directly.
Understand?
Okay.
After we finish sewing,
you can take a look here.
Because here,
did we have a hollow just now?
Did we have some hollow here just now?
Let's take a look again.
Look.
Is there a little hollow here?
Why is there a little hole here?
Because its sewing line type
has not been changed to TURN.
In our previous video,
I have repeatedly told you that
if you fold it up and sew it,
does this whole sheet
cover this shape?
Is it the bottom of this section
and this section are sewn together
and used to fix the position?
They are folded together.
So here,
the sewing line type
has to be changed to TURN.
If you hide the outer layer,
you will see that
these two layers are folded together.
Okay.
Next,
because the models in our Modular Configurator
use more fabric,
we can merge them
into the same default fabric.
Then,
in the attribute editor,
we can change the material attribute
of the fabric type
to Cotton Garbant.
It is a relatively hard one.
It is used to make khaki pants
and a relatively hard shirt fabric.
Or,
you can change it to
Cotton Heavy Tool
or Cotton Tool
fabric.
For this fabric,
you can see that
its different values,
that is,
the seam allowance,
the foot line strength,
are all a little less than
Cotton Garbant.
So,
it looks a little softer.
It looks like
there is a little bit
of a deep fold,
but it is not as soft
as Cotton Garbant,
because Cotton is not that hard.
Of course,
if you can't tell
how to use these fabrics,
you can add our skirt.
There are the skirt number
and password on the left side.
Go to the description
of the material attribute
and some of its usual
clothing types.
You can also use it
according to the formula.
As you can see just now,
I changed some
exaggerated poses.
I also wanted to see
the distribution of the fold.
Here,
today,
in the group,
some of my friends
also asked
why my button
disappeared suddenly.
It's like this.
For example,
when you have a large
range of motion,
or when you are very
intensively pulling the
panel,
the button
may be identified
on the wrong side.
It may be identified
on the back of the panel.
So,
here we need to hide
the virtual model
and find this button,
and then choose
to reset the 3D position.
It will automatically
be reset to the outside,
reset to its
original correct position.
In this way,
the button
will not be hidden
in the sleeve.
OK.
Now,
the whole part of the shirt
is almost over.
Outside the shirt,
because we want to make a vest,
we need to
adjust these
panels
in advance
to reduce
the conflict thickness.
Then,
the virtual model,
because we are using
the linear virtual model,
then we need to
reduce its surface diameter
to 1,
so that the air thickness
around it is relatively thin.
Then,
the clothes will be closer
to the virtual model.
Then,
we will reduce
the tail-to-toe ratio.
You can see that
when I reduce
the tail-to-toe ratio,
this panel
looks like
a tight dress.
To make it tight,
it is more convenient
for us to wear
a vest
on the outside.